Finding Aid for the William Bellin Papers, 1930-1996
UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections
- Series 6. Performance Design, 1954-1996; (Boxes 1-22)
  - George Jenkins Projects
    - Ice Capades - blueline drawings (19 items), 1960; Set pieces, including The Wizard of Oz, Operama, and A Salute to Rogers and Hammerstein, among others. (Box 9, Folder 0)
    - Jolly's Progress - blueline drawing, 1959; Station ground plan. (Box 9, Folder 0)
    - Jolly's Progress - playbill, 1959 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - La Boheme - blueline drawings (25 items), 1958 Jun-Aug; Primarily of props, attic, and Momu's caf. (Box 11, Folder 0)
    - La Boheme - photocopied sketches of sets (4 items), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Midnight Sun (The) - blueline drawing of set plan, no date (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Midnight Sun (The) - playbill, 1959 Nov 4-7 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Miracle Worker (The) - blueline drawings (38 items), 1959-60; Primarily of props, fences, doctor's office, tower, summer house, garden house, and playhouse. (Box 13, Folder 0)
    - Mr. Rumple - blueline drawings (10 items), 1957 Aug-Sep; Primarily of Barney's bar, Nelson's studio, park, and psychiatrist's office. One sheet labeled "Mr. Runkel." (Box 12, Folder 0)
    - Music with Mary Martin (television project) - original artwork of scenery details, 1959; Designs for border, theater, and Cinderella's clock. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Music with Mary Martin (television project) - studio schedule, 1959 Mar (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Music with Mary Martin (television) - blueline drawings (33 items), 1959; Primarily of masks, props, dressing room, Cinderella, and Peter Pan set plans. (Box 22, Folder 0)
    - Once More, With Feeling - blueline drawings and set scene sketches (29 items), 1958 May-Jul; Ground plan, apartment, doors, and fireplace. Set scene sketches of living rooms and dressing room scenes. (Box 14, Folder 0)
    - One More River - blueline drawings (9 items), 1960 Jan; Primarily of lifeboat and ground plan. (Box 12, Folder 0)
    - Paradise Island - blueline drawings (34 items), 1961; Primarily of volcano, lava, waterfall, mystery valley, caves, and village scene. Also includes stage and seating plan of Marine Theatre in Jones Beach, NY. (Box 15, Folder 0)
    - Paradise Island - playbills (2 items), no date (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Royal Hunt of the Sun (The) - playbills (2 items), no date; Appear to be for two different productions (London and New York). (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Song of Norway - blueline drawings (25 items), 1958-59, 1962; Primarily of Neptune's shell and fan, blocks of ice, and preliminary ground plans. Appears to be material for three separate productions (Jones Beach and Los Angeles). (Box 17, Folder 0)
    - Song of Norway - blueline drawings (28 items), 1958 Mar-Jun; Primarily of props, barges, house, chocolate shop, and Venice. (Box 16, Folder 0)
    - Song of Norway - copies of pencil sketches of various sets, no date (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Tall Story - original artwork of scenery details (5 items), ca. 1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Tall Story - playbill, ca. 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Tall Story - tracing paper sketch of village, no date (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Thousand Clowns (A) - blueline drawings and set scene sketches (4 items), 1962; Set plans for Arnold's office and light plot for apartment and office. Set scene sketches of Murray's apartment and Arnold's office. (Box 18, Folder 0)
    - Thousand Clowns (A) - playbill, 1962 Oct 22 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Two for the Seesaw - blueline drawings (18 items), 1957-58; Appears to be for productions in New York and London. New York includes drawings for Gittel and Jerry's rooms. London includes apartment designs and elevations. (Box 20, Folder 0)
  - Other Stage and Television Productions
    - Beach (The) - playbill, photograph, and clipping (Westwood Village Players), 1947 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Caligula - playbill and annotated clipping, 1960 Feb-Mar (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Chu Chem - playbill, 1966 Nov (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fade Out Fade In - playbill, 1964 Apr (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fade Out Fade In - tracing paper sketch and paper stencils, no date (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Garden of Sweets (The) - playbill, 1961 Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Hidden River - blueline drawing of Portal #1, 1956 Nov 23 (Box 12, Folder 0)
    - High Spirits - playbills (2 items), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Let it Ride! - playbill, 1961 Oct 9 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mame - playbill, 1966 Apr (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Much Ado About Nothing - playbill, 1959 Sep 21 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mystery of Elche (The) - design patterns and costume sketches, [ca. 1963] (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Mystery of Elche (The) - playbill, [ca. 1963] (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Oedipus - fabric samples, cast measurements, and helmet sketches, no date; Santa Fe Opera production. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Rehearsal (The) - blueline drawings of set plans and set scene sketch of unidentified scene (3 items), no date (Box 19, Folder 0)
    - Sketches, patterns, costume and set ideas, no date; Mostly unidentified material from folder originally annotated: "Romeo and Juliet masks; Misc notes Tempest, Caligula, Much Ado, Camelot, Antony and Cleopatra". Some pieces appear to be from Antony and Cleopatra, Much Ado, and Tempest. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sponono - blueline drawing for tentative light plot, no date (Box 19, Folder 0)
    - Studio One: Death and Life of Larry Benson - blueline drawings of set details (6 items), 1954; Mainly doors and windows. (Box 21, Folder 0)
    - Tempest (The) - playbill, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Traveller Without Luggage - blueline drawings (13 items), 1964; Props, scenery details, and ground plan. (Box 19, Folder 0)
    - Traveller Without Luggage - sketch, stencil, and photographs of fireplace and screen, no date (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified project - drawing of stage with actors, no date (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified project - paintings and stencil, no date (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified project - sketches on tracing paper, no date (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified project - snapshots of decorative litter (8), no date (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Zulu and the Zayda (The) - blueline drawing of set (1 item), 1965 (Box 19, Folder 0)
  - Sarasota Ballet
    - Peter and the Wolf - costume and design sketches, no date; With letter to Norah Jones from W.B. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Seasonal calendars and program book, 1993-96; With note to Norah Jones from W.B. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Walpurgis Night - copies of costume designs, no date; With letter to Norah Jones from W.B. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - UCLA
    - Caesar and Cleopatra - 2 playbills and 6 color transparencies of stage performance, 1956 May (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Caesar and Cleopatra - blueline drawings of set plans and scenic elements (27 items), 1956 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Caesar and Cleopatra - costume sketches (20 items), no date (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Caesar and Cleopatra - costume sketches with small fabric samples (16 items), no date; With 3 painted illustrations of stage scenes. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Caesar and Cleopatra - matted costume sketches with small fabric samples (4 items), no date (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Henry IV, Part One - 2 playbills with 3 color transparencies of stage performance, 1957 Apr (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Henry IV, Part One - blueline drawings of set plans (12 items), 1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Henry IV, Part One - costume sketches (5 items), no date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Henry IV, Part One - costume sketches with small fabric samples (1 of 2) (7 items), no date (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Henry IV, Part One - costume sketches with small fabric samples (2 of 2) (7items), no date (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Henry IV, Part One - matted costume sketches with small fabric samples (4 items), no date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Love of Four Colonels (The) - blueline drawings of set plans (9 items), 1954 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Love of Four Colonels (The) - playbill, 1954 Dec (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Tobias and the Angel - matted photograph of mask for Asmoday, 1954; Based on sculpture of Assyrian bird-headed god. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - UCLA Theater Arts productions - playbills/programs with crew credits for W.B. (6 items), 1953-55; Billy Budd, The Happy Time, The Inspector General, Marriage Wheel, Mayhem in Mayfair-Death in Dulwich, and Tobias and the Angel. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series 7. Professional Affiliations, ca. 1964-1984; (Boxes 2-3)
  The series contains a promotional publication for the United Scenic Artists and a lifetime achievement award for Bellin from the International Brotherhood of Painters dated 1984. The United Scenic Artists publication is targeted to hiring the organization's members for the 1964 New York World's Fair and Bellin is listed as a "designer" in the publication. There is no specific arrangement to the series.
    - International Brotherhood of Painters - lifetime achievement award for W.B., 1984 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Put "Theatre" in Your World's Fair Thinking - United Scenic Artists promotional booklet, ca. 1964; Promotional publication for hiring United Scenic Artists members for the 1964 New York World's Fair. Listing for Bellin under "designer". (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Series 8. Resumes, until 1980; (Box 1)
  The series consists of a small number of Bellin's resumes. The resumes are not dated or arranged in a specific order.
    - Variety of resumes reflecting the career of W.B., before 1980; Resumes for display, theater, circus, and graphic design work. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series 9. Writings by Bellin, no date; (Boxes 3, 23)
  The series is comprised of undated manuscript pages and notes for what is believed to be an unpublished book written by Bellin. The book focuses on prop-making, designing scenery and elements of designing costumes for many uses, such as displays, theater, and motion pictures. There is no specific arrangement to the series.
    - Bellin, William - letter to Norah Jones regarding his book, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Book notes, no date (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Book notes on index cards, no date (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Book notes - draft and roughs, no date (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Book notes written on paper pads, no date (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Drafts of outgoing letters requesting advice or monetary support, no date (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript pages for unpublished book (no title) written by W.B., no date; Focused on prop-making, designing scenery, and elements of designing costumes for displays, theater, and motion pictures. (Box 3, Folder 1)